# REINARD PAGDILAO | FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

As a committed and passionate full stack software engineer with a background of BSBA in Economics, my goal is to deliver clean, concise, effective and efficient code specializing in React (MERN), TypeScript, and Python. With the foundation of an analytical mindset and experience in a fast-paced high pressure environment, I am highly capable of understanding complex tasks, pinpointing causes of errors, and learning the necessary tech stacks required. I have excellent interpersonal communication and teamwork skills that can contribute towards a company's culture and atmosphere in a positive experience.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages - JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, HTML, CSS | Libraries/Frameworks - React, Node.js, Express.js, BootStrap Database - MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, Mongoose, ODM, ORM | Other - RESTful Routing JSON, OOP proficient

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

May 2021 - PRESENT

Viberant - Full-stack application containing a social meetup aspect that allows users to find, create, and join events

- Implemented MERN (MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js) tech stacks and applied Bootstrap/ Styled-Components for styling deployed through Heroku/Netlify
- Worked in a team environment consisting of a github manager, two front-end devs, and a back-end dev
- Collaborated with General Assembly's UX/UI Design cohort discussing the creation of our full- stack application and its concepts/design, where we utilized whiteboard/wireframe applications such as Figma and Miro
- Applied Json Web Token and Bcrypt for security of our CRUD routes and for users' private information

NBA Bite - Full-stack application that retrieves and organizes NBA player statistics from an API to client side

- Made RESTful API axios calls to an Express, Express Layouts, Node.js backend handling all create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations, and tested all backend routes during development using Postman.
- Implemented EJS tagged literals for client side display along with CSS3 to provide style and flexbox layout
- Used PostGres to define schemas for MySQL collections
- Created a TypeScript conversion with proper Postgres setup and Javascript defined types

Magikarp Tourney Pro - Front-end based web game containing animation, movement applications, and basic OOP

- Vanilla Javascript, CSS3, HTML5, and display animated visuals through HTML5 Canvas
- Utilize coding fundamentals to create a game that catches five randomly weighted appearing fish with obstacles
- Implemented JS techniques such as constructor functions, array iterations, conditionals, and necessary initialization
- Utilized Git control during the production of the application with frequent commits until deployment

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

General Assembly - Teaching Assistant | Remote

August 2021 - Present

 Referred position for top cohort students, reinforced General Assembly's Software Immersive curriculum by guiding and debugging current students' coding errors in a a self-efficient manner

Buffalo Wild Wings - Server | Las Vegas, NV

August 2017 - May 2021

- Attended a 10+ table section with a range of 2-6 guests per table, often hosting local 10+ persons sports teams. Long standing employment for 3+ years in a 73% annual turnover rate industry
- Communicated interpersonally while pushing a minimum of \$1000 sales per shift and maintained professionalism in a high demand high volume environment, 300+ guests during peak times

## **EDUCATION**

**General Assembly | Remote** 

2021

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

University of Nevada, Las Vegas | Las Vegas, Nevada

2019

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration - BSBA in Economics